PRINCIPAL PROGRAM MANAGER, DATA LOSS PREVENTION

Core Accomplishments

- Outstanding ability to develop implementation strategies and best practices for large-scale projects, build trusted alliances with senior executives, and support a network of global managers
- Held numerous management and individual contributor roles, culminating in Program Leadership for \$22B OEM Global Readiness Division.
 Doubled as Chief of Staff to Senior Director. Rated in top 10% of Microsoft employees, receiving numerous top performer awards across 10+ years, including Microsoft IT MVP Award honoring one recipient each year within the entire division
- Led System Test and User Training for the company's largest state-of-the-art printing conversion efforts, eliminating more than \$5M in operating costs through system installations/upgrades in Texas and California. Won the "Excellence in Service Award" reserved for the top 1% of enterprise-wide employees

Professional Experience

Principal Program Manager, Data Loss Prevention January 2013 to Current Bickford Senior Living it/4 Suffolk, VA

- Took leadership over senior program managers leading next-generation SaaS and on-premises projects for Data Loss Prevention and User Authorization product groups. Prior to this promotion, brought oversight and order to Scrum Development and Sustaining Engineering, while building and tuning 25+ processes across the product lifecycle. Won awards for timely deliveries and internal/external client satisfaction.
 Engineering & Release Operations Program Management
- Oversee both Engineering and Release Operations for the launch of the very first SaaS solution out of the Data Loss Prevention product group while managing team integration and product release for newly acquired User Authorization product group.
- Direct the efforts of 7 Senior Program Managers stationed in San Francisco and Pune, including capacity planning and talent sourcing to address program demand increase. Process Reengineering
- Analyze SaaS deployment scenarios and customer feedback leading to the clarification of roles, assignments, deliverables, and channels for 20 cross-functional staff.
- Enhanced inter-departmental communication between Engineering and Legal, cutting laborious legal review process from 3-4 months to just
 a few weeks.
- Oversaw three 10-member Scrum teams running in parallel to deliver feature as well as sustaining engineering releases on 3-week sprints. Drove high-level feature strategy including sprint planning, backlog grooming, and retrospectives.
- Drove QA, Development, Product, and Support teams up to the VP level to handle hot fixes for JPMC, Bank of America, AmEx, Industrial Commerce Bank of China, Bank of Tokyo, and other high-value clients. Process Reengineering
- Introduced operations layer to run concurrent with development, eliminating chronic release delays. Refined processes around compliance, BOM development, product mastering, and licensing.
- Expanded Release Readiness checklist to cover operations, marketing, product documentation, support, training, and field readiness (in addition to engineering).

User Acceptance Test Manager

January 2002 to January 2013 OEM Global Readiness Division i1/4 City, STATE Microsoft Redmond, WA 2002-2013 Held numerous management and individual contributor roles, culminating in Program Leadership for \$22B OEM Global Readiness Division. Doubled as Chief of Staff to Senior Director. Rated in top 10% of Microsoft employees, receiving numerous top performer awards across 10+ years, including Microsoft IT MVP Award honoring one recipient each year within the entire division. * Drove rhythm of the business for strategic projects on behalf of the executive leadership and partner teams, including fiscal planning and management, internal / external executive communications, roadmap planning, Key Performance Indicators (KPIs), workforce and performance management, and delivery of global program portfolio. * Provided interface between Operations and Product teams to clarify roles and responsibilities, dependencies, and shared accountabilities for program planning, development and releases, eliminating 6-12 month downstream delays. * Partnered closely with executive leadership in managing end-to-end delivery of the OEM Division's most extensive code base overhaul of the enterprise licensing system. * Facilitated crossgeography system release efforts across Engineering, IT, and Operations, earning numerous leadership awards for exceeding aggressive delivery goals and customer expectations. * Implemented DevOps Release Management standards, leading to the successful delivery of 8 large-scale quarterly releases while decreasing defects and enhancement backlog 50%. * Drove anti-piracy (AP) efforts for Microsoft Office, Windows, Server and Tools product launches, including development of new anti-piracy security features. * Orchestrated an anti-piracy coalition and inaugural Anti-Piracy symposium to cultivate executive-level alliances with Fortune 500 technology firms such as Cisco, Intuit, and Disney. * Drove operational planning, organization, direction and management of multi-stream activities for building and maintaining frequent, concurrent software and infrastructure releases for promotion through a series of pre-production environments, ultimately leading to successful product releases. * Implemented standard business processes, procedures and best practices that addressed and governed the risk tolerance of the organization, while collaborating with stakeholders to coordinate change requests and regulatory / corporate compliance requirements, * Partnered directly with Engineering, Test, Operations, and executive leadership to deliver large-scale, end-to-end releases for Microsoff's enterprise systems. * Managed code migration, including scheduling, coordination and change requests for outages within the environments to perform upgrades, patching and other IT releases and service activities. * Drove continuous integration and continuous improvements, while strengthening the definition of release readiness and implementing the System Release Playbook, considered best practice across Microsoft IT. * Identified, developed, and implemented sustained test standards and processes for critical enterprise-wide and customer facing applications and ecommerce platform * Responsible for leading change to improve effectiveness, issue resolution, realize cost savings and drive scalability, standardization and productivity, resulting in savings of \$500K in vendor costs and average 3 month reduction in test cycles. January 1999 to January 2001 Charles Schwab it/4 City, STATE Led System Test and User Training for the company's largest state-of-the-art

printing conversion efforts, eliminating more than \$5M in operating costs through system installations/upgrades in Texas and California. Won the "Excellence in Service Award" reserved for the top 1% of enterprise-wide employees.

Education

Bachelor of Arts: (CSM), Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO), Project Management University of California i'/4 City, State, US Bachelor of Arts in Sociology, University of California, Davis ITIL Foundations for IT Service Management, Certified Scrum Master (CSM), Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO), Certified Microsoft Standards Professional (CMSP), Six Sigma Green Belt, Project Management Fundamentals Certifications

ITIL Foundations for IT Service Management, Certified Scrum Master (CSM), Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO), Certified Microsoft Standards Professional (CMSP), Six Sigma Green Belt, Project Management Fundamentals Skills

Award, Model-view-presenter, Mvp, Operations, Program Manager, Data Loss Prevention, Loss Prevention, Training, Large-scale, Saas, Software As A Service, Printing, Integration, Integrator, Product Lifecycle, Satisfaction, Clarify, Executive Communications, Performance Management, Oem, Scheduling, Ecommerce, User Acceptance, Ap, Cisco, Microsoft Office, Ms Office, Security, Bom, Clients, Documentation, Marketing, Product Documentation, Qa, Best Practices, Project Management, Capacity Planning, Deployment, Increase, Program Management, San, Storage Area Network, Switch Capacity, Itil, Six Sigma, Six-sigma